var words = 
[
    {
        "question": "الَّذِي",
        "answer": "The one who",
        "pcklId": "1434",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "alladhī",
        "frequency": "1464",
        "surahnum": "104",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِي جَمَعَ مَالًا وَعَدَّدَهُ",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الَّتِي",
        "answer": "Which",
        "pcklId": "1435",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "allatī",
        "frequency": "1464",
        "surahnum": "104",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " الَّتِي تَطَّلِعُ عَلَى الْأَفْئِدَةِ",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "اللَّهِ",
        "answer": "Allah",
        "pcklId": "2841",
        "rootWordId": 61,
        "tlit": "l-lahi",
        "frequency": "2851",
        "surahnum": "104",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " نَارُ اللَّهِ الْمُوقَدَةُ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱللَّه",
        "waznEnglish": "Allah",
        "waznTlit": "allah",
        "waznType": "Proper noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "جَمَعَ",
        "answer": "collects",
        "pcklId": "21",
        "rootWordId": 260,
        "tlit": "jamaʿa",
        "frequency": "129",
        "surahnum": "104",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِي جَمَعَ مَالًا وَعَدَّدَهُ",
        "rootWord": "ج م ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَمَعَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to gather, to collect",
        "waznTlit": "jamaʿa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَحْسَبُ",
        "answer": "Thinking",
        "pcklId": "43",
        "rootWordId": 316,
        "tlit": "yaḥsabu",
        "frequency": "109",
        "surahnum": "104",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " يَحْسَبُ أَنَّ مَالَهُ أَخْلَدَهُ",
        "rootWord": "ح س ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَسِبَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to think",
        "waznTlit": "ḥasiba",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْحُطَمَةِ",
        "answer": "the Crusher",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 334,
        "tlit": "l-ḥuṭamati",
        "frequency": "6",
        "surahnum": "104",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " كَلَّا لَيُنْبَذَنَّ فِي الْحُطَمَةِ",
        "rootWord": "ح ط م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حُطَمَة",
        "waznEnglish": "lest not crush you",
        "waznTlit": "ḥuṭamat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْحُطَمَةُ",
        "answer": "the Crusher (is)",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 334,
        "tlit": "l-ḥuṭamatu",
        "frequency": "6",
        "surahnum": "104",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا أَدْرَاكَ مَا الْحُطَمَةُ",
        "rootWord": "ح ط م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حُطَمَة",
        "waznEnglish": "lest not crush you",
        "waznTlit": "ḥuṭamat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَخْلَدَهُ",
        "answer": "will make him immortal",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 426,
        "tlit": "akhladahu",
        "frequency": "87",
        "surahnum": "104",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " يَحْسَبُ أَنَّ مَالَهُ أَخْلَدَهُ",
        "rootWord": "خ ل د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَخْلَدَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to adhere",
        "waznTlit": "akhlada",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَدْرَاكَ",
        "answer": "will make you know",
        "pcklId": "28",
        "rootWordId": 469,
        "tlit": "adrāka",
        "frequency": "29",
        "surahnum": "104",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا أَدْرَاكَ مَا الْحُطَمَةُ",
        "rootWord": "د ر ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَدْرَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make known",
        "waznTlit": "adrā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَطَّلِعُ",
        "answer": "mounts up",
        "pcklId": "9",
        "rootWordId": 920,
        "tlit": "taṭṭaliʿu",
        "frequency": "19",
        "surahnum": "104",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " الَّتِي تَطَّلِعُ عَلَى الْأَفْئِدَةِ",
        "rootWord": "ط ل ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "طَّلَعَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to look",
        "waznTlit": "ṭalaʿa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَعَدَّدَهُ",
        "answer": "and counts it",
        "pcklId": "7",
        "rootWordId": 964,
        "tlit": "waʿaddadahu",
        "frequency": "57",
        "surahnum": "104",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِي جَمَعَ مَالًا وَعَدَّدَهُ",
        "rootWord": "ع د د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَدَّدَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to count",
        "waznTlit": "ʿaddada",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "عَمَدٍ",
        "answer": "columns",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 1019,
        "tlit": "ʿamadin",
        "frequency": "7",
        "surahnum": "104",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فِي عَمَدٍ مُمَدَّدَةٍ",
        "rootWord": "ع م د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَمَد",
        "waznEnglish": "intended",
        "waznTlit": "ʿamad",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَفْئِدَةِ",
        "answer": "the hearts",
        "pcklId": "15",
        "rootWordId": 1098,
        "tlit": "l-afidati",
        "frequency": "16",
        "surahnum": "104",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " الَّتِي تَطَّلِعُ عَلَى الْأَفْئِدَةِ",
        "rootWord": "ف أ د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ف أ د",
        "waznEnglish": "their hearts",
        "waznTlit": "fā hamza dāl",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِكُلِّ",
        "answer": "to every",
        "pcklId": "358",
        "rootWordId": 1288,
        "tlit": "likulli",
        "frequency": "377",
        "surahnum": "104",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَيْلٌ لِكُلِّ هُمَزَةٍ لُمَزَةٍ",
        "rootWord": "ك ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كُلّ",
        "waznEnglish": "(is) a burden",
        "waznTlit": "kull",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لُمَزَةٍ",
        "answer": "backbiter",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 1349,
        "tlit": "lumazatin",
        "frequency": "4",
        "surahnum": "104",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَيْلٌ لِكُلِّ هُمَزَةٍ لُمَزَةٍ",
        "rootWord": "ل م ز",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "لُّمَزَة",
        "waznEnglish": "criticizes you",
        "waznTlit": "lumazat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُمَدَّدَةٍ",
        "answer": "extended",
        "pcklId": "30",
        "rootWordId": 1379,
        "tlit": "mumaddadatin",
        "frequency": "32",
        "surahnum": "104",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فِي عَمَدٍ مُمَدَّدَةٍ",
        "rootWord": "م د د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّمَدَّدَة",
        "waznEnglish": "and prolongs them",
        "waznTlit": "mumaddadat",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَالًا",
        "answer": "wealth",
        "pcklId": "83",
        "rootWordId": 1427,
        "tlit": "mālan",
        "frequency": "86",
        "surahnum": "104",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِي جَمَعَ مَالًا وَعَدَّدَهُ",
        "rootWord": "م و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "م و ل",
        "waznEnglish": "[the] wealth",
        "waznTlit": "mīm wāw lām",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَالَهُ",
        "answer": "his wealth",
        "pcklId": "84",
        "rootWordId": 1427,
        "tlit": "mālahu",
        "frequency": "86",
        "surahnum": "104",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " يَحْسَبُ أَنَّ مَالَهُ أَخْلَدَهُ",
        "rootWord": "م و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "م و ل",
        "waznEnglish": "[the] wealth",
        "waznTlit": "mīm wāw lām",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَيُنْبَذَنَّ",
        "answer": "Surely he will be thrown",
        "pcklId": "9",
        "rootWordId": 1436,
        "tlit": "layunbadhanna",
        "frequency": "12",
        "surahnum": "104",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " كَلَّا لَيُنْبَذَنَّ فِي الْحُطَمَةِ",
        "rootWord": "ن ب ذ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَبَذَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to throw, to cast",
        "waznTlit": "nabadha",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَارُ",
        "answer": "A Fire",
        "pcklId": "143",
        "rootWordId": 1529,
        "tlit": "nāru",
        "frequency": "194",
        "surahnum": "104",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " نَارُ اللَّهِ الْمُوقَدَةُ",
        "rootWord": "ن و ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَار",
        "waznEnglish": "a fire",
        "waznTlit": "nār",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "هُمَزَةٍ",
        "answer": "slanderer",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 1563,
        "tlit": "humazatin",
        "frequency": "3",
        "surahnum": "104",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَيْلٌ لِكُلِّ هُمَزَةٍ لُمَزَةٍ",
        "rootWord": "ه م ز",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "هُمَزَة",
        "waznEnglish": "Defamer",
        "waznTlit": "humazat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُؤْصَدَةٌ",
        "answer": "closed over",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1617,
        "tlit": "mu'ṣadatun",
        "frequency": "3",
        "surahnum": "104",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّهَا عَلَيْهِمْ مُؤْصَدَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "و ص د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّؤْصَدَة",
        "waznEnglish": "closed in",
        "waznTlit": "mu'ṣadat",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُوقَدَةُ",
        "answer": "kindled",
        "pcklId": "10",
        "rootWordId": 1636,
        "tlit": "l-mūqadatu",
        "frequency": "11",
        "surahnum": "104",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " نَارُ اللَّهِ الْمُوقَدَةُ",
        "rootWord": "و ق د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُوقَدَة",
        "waznEnglish": "they kindled",
        "waznTlit": "mūqadat",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form IV)"
    }
]; 
export default words;